5pointz.co.uk 2017-07-15

# Privacy Policy | 5Pointz

## 1\. WHAT WE COLLECT

We will treat all your Personal Information as confidential (although we reserve the right to disclose this information in the circumstances set out below). We will keep it on a secure server and we will fully comply with all applicable UK Data Protection and consumer legislation from time to time in place.

  * When you shop with 5 Pointz, we will ask you to input and will collect Personal Information from you such as your name, e-mail address, billing address, delivery address, telephone number, product selections, credit card or other payment information and a password.

  * We may also collect, and our third party providers of advertisements and content may collect, information about where you are on the internet (eg the URL you came from, IP address, domain types like .co.uk and .com), your browser type, the country and telephone area code where your computer is located, the pages of our website that were viewed during your visit, the advertisements you clicked on, and any search terms that you entered on our website ("User Information").

  * We may collect this information even if you do not register with us.

  * You should be aware that this site is being monitored and may capture information about your visit that will help us improve the quality of our service, or be used to present you with 5 Pointz products which are relevant to your browsing history when you visit other websites. To find out more about cookies [click here](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/HTTP_cookie) (opens in a new window - please note that we're not responsible for the content of external websites). 

## 2\. WHAT DO WE DO WITH THE INFORMATION WE COLLECT 

We confirm that any Personal Information which you provide to us (or which is available on public registers) and any User Information from which we can identify you, is held in accordance with the registration we have with the Data Commissioner's Office. We use your information only for the following purposes:

  * Processing your orders.

  * For statistical or survey purposes to improve this Website and its services to you.

  * To serve website content and advertisements to you.

  * To administer this website; to contact you about leaving a review on a product once your order has been completed.

  * If you consent, to notify you of products or special offers that may be of interest to you. You agree that you do not object to us contacting you for any of the above purposes whether by telephone, e-mail or in writing and you confirm that you do not and will not consider any of the above as being a breach of any of your rights under the Privacy and Electronic Communications (EC Directive) Regulations 2003.

  * When you create a shopping account while ordering online you will be given the option to receive information from 5 Pointz by post, e-mail or telephone, about products, promotions or special offers which we feel may be of interest to you. In the event that you do not wish to be contacted for such purposes, ensure that you untick the appropriate box as you go through the registration process. You may unsubscribe from our contact list at any time by clicking the unsubscribe link at the bottom of any e-mail that we send to you when opting in to email marketting, or by e-mailing us at info@5pointz.co.uk or calling us on 0117 945 0555 between 9am and 5pm Monday to Friday.

  * Your Personal Information may be disclosed to reputable third parties who will help process your order. 5 Pointz requires all such third parties to treat your personal information as fully confidential and to fully comply with all applicable UK Data Protection and consumer legislation from time to time in place. We will not release your Personal Information to any company outside of 5 Pointz for mailing or marketing purposes.

  * You should be aware that if we are requested by the police or any other regulatory or government authority investigating suspected illegal activities to provide your Personal Information and /or User Information, we are entitled do so.

When entering any of our contests or prize draws, you provide your name, email address and mailing address. If you win, we will send the prize to the address entered and notify you by email. When you enter a contest or prize draw, you are also included in our newsletter list to receive notice of promotions, specials and new additions to the Website. You may unsubscribe from this news list by following the unsubscribe instructions in any email received.

We use Cookies to keep track of your current shopping session to personalise your experience and so that you may retrieve your shopping basket at any time; if you do not accept Cookies, you will be unable to use this Website for shopping purposes, only for browsing and research. If you'd like to opt out of cookies, please go to the Network Advertising Initiative website (opens in a new window - please note that we're not responsible for the content of external websites).

Delivery photography: If one of our Customer Delivery Partners attempts to deliver an order to your address and finds there's no-one available to receive it, we reserve the right to take a photograph of the outside of the property to assure you we were in the right geographical location to fulfill your order, and confirm we had located the correct address. We can assure you that this photograph won't be published or circulated, or used for any other purpose other than verification, and that it's held securely in compliance with Data Protection legislation.

## 3\. WHY DO WE NEED THE INFORMATION WE COLLECT

We require this information to understand your needs and provide you with a better service, and in particular for the following reasons:

  * Internal record keeping. We may use the information to improve our products and services.

  * We may periodically send promotional emails about new products, special offers or other information which we think you may find interesting using the email address which you have provided.

  * From time to time, we may also use your information to contact you for market research purposes.

  * We may contact you by email, phone, fax or mail.

  * We may use the information to customise the website according to your interests.

## 4\. SECURITY

We are committed to ensuring that your information is secure. In order to prevent unauthorised access or disclosure, we have put in place suitable physical, electronic and managerial procedures to safeguard and secure the information we collect online.

## 5\. HOW WE USE COOKIES

A cookie is a small file which asks permission to be placed on your computer's hard drive. Once you agree, the file is added and the cookie helps analyse web traffic or lets you know when you visit a particular site. Cookies allow web applications to respond to you as an individual. The web application can tailor its operations to your needs, likes and dislikes by gathering and remembering information about your preferences. We use traffic log cookies to identify which pages are being used. This helps us analyse data about web page traffic and improve our website in order to tailor it to customer needs. We only use this information for statistical analysis purposes and then the data is removed from the system. Overall, cookies help us provide you with a better website, by enabling us to monitor which pages you find useful and which you do not. A cookie in no way gives us access to your computer or any information about you, other than the data you choose to share with us. You can choose to accept or decline cookies. Most web browsers automatically accept cookies, but you can usually modify your browser setting to decline cookies if you prefer. This may prevent you from taking full advantage of the website.

## 6\. PROMOTIONAL DISCOUNTS

Promotional discounts & Prize Draws Coupons, discounts and promotional discount codes offered by 5 Pointz are valid only for use as part of a purchase made via 5pointz.co.uk unless otherwise stated. Such promotional discounts are not valid for use as part of a purchase in store, or for telephone orders.

## 7\. CONTEST & PRIZE DRAWS

When entering any of our contests or prize draws, you provide your name, email address and mailing address. If you win, we will send the prize to the address entered and notify you by email. When you enter a contest or prize draw, you are also included in our newsletter list to receive notice of promotions, specials and new additions to the website. You may unsubscribe from this news list by following the unsubscribe instructions in any email received. 

GO UP!
